()

Melbourne, VIC



kuldeepdawar47@gmail.com



0452 492 629



Australian Work Rights

ABOUT ME

I'm an ambitious and passionate Junior Full Stack Developer with 3 years of experience. I recently completed my masters and an extensive work based learning program having successfully delivered complex projects and teach coding to clients predominantly in the education sector. I am highly technical, detailoriented and have a methodical attitude towards the engineering and project process. I am confident in my ability to add value to an organisation with my diverse experience and unique skill set. I have been known for good understanding of agile methodologies for Quick client feedback. I am a clear communicator with strong presentation, investigative, problemsolving and decision-making skills with extensive technical leadership. I enjoy emerging technologies and have a strong dedication to my work. I am seeking an exciting start to my career in technology and I am confident in my ability to add value to an React Developer role.

TECHNICAL

React	
React Router	••••
Redux	••••
JavaScript	••••
HTML/CSS	••••
WordPress	00000
PHP	00000
RESTfulAPI's	00000
Windows 7,8,10	00000
Node.js	••••
GitHub	••••
TypeScript	••••

EDUCATION

- Master of Information & Communication
 Technology University
 of Sunshine Coast, 2019 2020
- Bachelor of Computer Science (Computer Science & Engineering)
 Kurukshetra University, 2011 – 2014

KULDEEP SINGH



JNR. FULLSTACK DEVELOPER | WEB DEVELOPER | REACT DEVELOPER

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Dynamic and results-driven professional with extensive experience as Full Stack Web Developer,
 Freelance Developer, Computer Programmer Teacher and Tutor.
- Successful working in a team environment, as well as leading group projects.
- Expansive knowledge of React, UI/UX, Complex technology environments and Web Development.
- Hands-on experience in identifying web-based user interaction along with designing and implementing highly responsive user interface components by deploying React concepts.
- Proficient in translating designs & wireframes into high-quality code, and writing application interface code via JavaScript and ReactJS workflows.
- Persuasive communicator with the ability to liaise at all levels and build stakeholder relationships, vendors and partners.
- Experienced in leading projects with brands such as Reesby, Om Sai Para Medical College, ARC Education and TCILC-IT Education & Training.
- Possesses outstanding technical aptitude, understanding of emotional intelligence and customer service, the drive and determination to achieve results.
- Developing and establishing engineering processes, developing team training materials and documentation for new development procedures and methods for complex environments.
- Communications Equipment Installation, Maintenance & Support. Oversee and manage the technical teams and ensure adherence to OHS and risk mitigation strategies.
- Passion for learning new areas such as Machine Learning, 4G and 5G and IoT.
- The ability to work under intense pressure and multi-task to meet deadlines or complete critical tasks.
- The ability to delegate responsibilities and deliver business outcomes as a team.
- Creating wireframes, prototypes and implementing complex UIs

SKILLS

- AWS Cloud services S3, DynamoDB, Elastic beanstalk, CodeCommit.
- C, C#, VHDL, Embedded C Languages
- Arduino IDE, ESP8266 Microcontrollers
- Team Leadership
- Ionic Framework, React, Nodejs
- Project organization
- Problem Resolution
- Notepad++
- Sublime, PyCharm
- jQuery, PayPal, Stripe, Braintree
- GitHub, AWS CodeCommit
- Adobe XD

- Oral and written communication
- Prototype development
- Oscilloscope, Digital Multimeter, Digital Circuits
- MATLAB, Simulink, AutoCAD
- Altium Designer, PCB layout
- Troubleshooting skills
- MySQL, SQL, MongoDB
- Lavarel, Magento, Bootstrap, Flask/Django
- HTML5, CSS3, Phyton/Django
- AI/Machine Learning, C/C++
- Photoshop
- TypeScript

EMPLOYMENT OVERVIEW

- Full Stack Developer Reesby Jan 2021 Current
 - Freelance Developer Om Sai Para Medical College Aug 2018 Dec 2018
- Web Developer **Self-Employed** Aug 2017 Jul 2018
 - Computer Programmer Teacher ARC Education Mar 2016 Jul 2017
- Industrial Training Tutor ARC Education Dec 2015 Feb 2016
 - Internship TCILC-IT Education & Training Jun 2015 Nov 2015

CERTIFICATE

- o 2020 Complete Python Bootcamp.
- React (Hooks, React Router, Redux)
- Python and Django Full Stack Web Developer Bootcamp.
- 2021 Python for Machine Learning & Data Science.
- Ultimate AWS Certified Solution Architect Associate 2020.

CORE SKILLS

- Team Leadership & Development
- Translating UI/UX design Frameworks
- Word-press CMS / Woo-commerce
- Managed plugins/tools and WordPress
- Containerization
- Strong Presentation Skills
- Highly Proactive Approach to Tasks
- Team Management & Development
- Time Management Skills
- Strong Influencing / Persuasion
- Build & maintain key relationships
- Strategic Business Developer
- Highly Motivated Self-Starter

BEHAVIOURAL

- Analytical thinking and conceptual problem-solving ability.
- I thrive on critical analysis and solution generation, taking into account bigger picture business issues.
- Trust, integrity and commitment to my work.
- Collaboration and relationship building ability - I connect easily to people at all levels and cross-culturally and possess well-honed interpersonal skills.
- Professional with strong written communications and formal report writing ability.
- Planning and organising ability including prioritising, management and project management skills.
- Tenacious and disciplined, my work ethic is sound and values and ethics are important to me.
- Leadership and team motivation.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Developer

Reesby (Contract) Jan 2021 – Current

 Working with a team of engineers on a CRM Project using AI / Machine Learning which uses python on the backend. Also working on a Web-based CRM which is Java-based (Back end) Website, and React (Front end), AWS, TypeScript, MongoDB, Node+, etc.

- Participated in all phases of system development life cycle, from requirements analysis through project implementation.
- Monitored and tested application performance to identify potential bottlenecks, develop solutions, and collaborate with developers on solution implementation.
- Troubleshoot interface software and debugged application codes to improve functionality and performance.
- Utilized React for its efficient data flow architecture to create a lightweight and render efficient web app that searched projects via the GitHub API through keywords.

Freelance Developer

Om Sai Para Medical College - www.ospmi.com

Aug 2018 - Dec 2018

- According to the client requirements, content update, speed issue, insert the keywords related to SEO, check weekly report for SEO, update the gallery.
- Resolve mail server issue like speed issue and registration forms update according to client requirement.
- Manage Google ad-word campaign keyword and every year domain renews and hosting and SSL certification also

Web Developer

Self-Employed

Aug 2017 - Jul 2018

- Developing frontend/Backend website architecture, displaying data on the Site and installing software, patching, upgrading and maintenance of the operating system.
- Refine specification and fulfil requirements based on their needs like added data, pages, databases functionality.

Computer Programmer Teacher

ARC Education

Mar 2016 - Jul 2017

- Installing, upgrading, and maintaining, hardware components as per requirement and perform a different kind of functionalities, design website including Front-end and Back-end.
- Finds problems and fix different types of error for students and create projects designed to enhance and teach to students how to build a website and its working.
- Create projects designed to enhance and teach to students how to build a website and its working.

Industrial Training

ARC Education

Dec 2015 - Feb 2016

- Building foundation skills for a low-level programming language to a high level and understand the
 algorithms.
- Understand program function and work with different syntax and hands-on experience of Python on realworld projects developing key skills covering basic to advanced level.

Internship

TCILC-IT Education & Training

Jun 2015 - Nov 2015

Internship Opportunity / Trainee Program given a practical work-placement program designed to provide a
professional experience in different areas related to Programming (Basic, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, PHP
Developer/ designer, Web design, MySQL, Photoshop etc.).

PROJECTS

Personal Portfolio - https://kuldeep-singh-portfolio.netlify.app/

Online Furniture - https://e-furniture24.com/

Developed a furniture website and different kinds of categories like Chair, Sofa, bed, and other products etc. based on the client's requirement, the website built in PHP, HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap etc.

${\bf Pizza~Order~System~(PYTHON)-\underline{https://github.com/kuldeepdawa/Pizza-order}}$

The Pizza Order System project built based on customer requirement how customers can give the number of Pizza Orders. Order payment received by the system and fulfils the customer requirement.

Southbank2020 – Machine Learning - https://github.com/kuldeepdawa/Machine-Learning-Project
A medium-size company has given one-year data about the online purchase that their customer has made.

They want the data analysis of the data using statistical and machine learning techniques.

IMAGEBAZAAR - Python/Django

Created a portfolio website which allows adding myriad of categories, according to their requirement and we can perform any function easily. I want to build the website in less time that why I used the Django framework. I used because Django is a high-level framework who provide a high level maintainable, fast, and secure website.

https://github.com/kuldeepdawa/React-Login-Form https://github.com/kuldeepdawa/Singlepageapp https://github.com/kuldeepdawa/React-to-list-app https://github.com/Kuldeepdawar